CORINA FLORESCU

University of North Texas, Denton, Texas $(+1)682-429-6123 \diamond CorinaFlorescu@my.unt.edu$

SUMMARY

Research scientist with 4+ years of academic experience. I work in an area between machine learning, natural language processing and text-mining. My research concerns the development of new methods to identify short phrases in the text of a document such that those phrases best capture the topics of the target document. I have developed several methods which benefits the indexing in scholarly. I am well connected in the academic community and have been presenting my work/tutorials to various natural language processing and data mining conferences.

EDUCATION

Doctor of Philosophy, Computer Science

January 2015 - Present

University of North Texas, Denton, Texas

Master of Science, Databases

2008 - 2010

University of Bucharest, Bucharest, Romania

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science and Mathematics

2004 - 2008

University of Bucharest, Bucharest, Romania

TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

Programming Languages
Software & Tools

Python, Java, LaTeX, C++, MySQL, MATLAB

TensorFlow, Keras, Weka, Hadoop

EXPERIENCE

Research Assistant

January 2015 - Present

University of North Texas, Denton, Texas

- · Developed keyphrase extraction systems for extracting keyphrases from scholarly documents; This extraction task aids indexing of documents in digital libraries, and hence, leads to improved organization, search, retrieval, and recommendation of scientific documents.
- · Developed a feature learning framework for automatically discover patterns that keyphrases express.
- · Developed a domain-independent supervised keyphrase extraction systems based on the learned representations.
- · Developed a ranking model to keyphrase extraction, such that the model can rank keyphrases according to their degree of representing the topic of a target document.

Computer Science Teacher

September 2008 - October 2012

I. L. Caragiale High School, Bucharest, Romania.

- \cdot Worked in a team of six people and came up with a model of Dragon with movable wings
- · Taught programming languages (C++, SQL, PL/SQL, PHP)
- · Designed lecture plans
- · Evaluated students performance

SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

Wei Jin, Corina Florescu. Improving Search and Retrieval in Digital Libraries by Leveraging Keyphrase Extraction Systems. In: Proceedings of the Joint Conference on Digital Libraries (JCDL 2018).

Corina Florescu, Wei Jin. Learning Feature Representations for Keyphrase Extraction. In: Proceedings of the American Association for Artificial Intelligence (AAAI 2018).

Corina Florescu, Cornelia Caragea. PositionRank: An Unsupervised Approach to Keyphrase Extraction from Scholarly Documents. In: Proceedings of the Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL 2017).

Corina Florescu, Cornelia Caragea. A Position-Biased PageRank Algorithm for Keyphrase Extraction. In: Proceedings of the American Association for Artificial Intelligence (AAAI 2017).

FELLOWSHIPS & GRANTS

Scholarship from American Association for Artificial Intelligence

Travel Grant from Women in Machine Learning

Toulouse Graduate School(TGS) Tuition Benefit Scholarship

ACADEMIC SERVICE

Manuscript peer review, Natural Language Engineering Journal

Manuscript peer review, Transactions on Knowledge Discovery from Data

Manuscript peer review, Language Resources and Evaluation

PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS

Association for Computing Machinery (ACM)

Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence (AAAI)